Full Stack Web Developer | Javascript | React | SQL | Express | Node LYNNWOOD, WA 98037

(707) 342.7380 | HALEYLOWEO@GMAIL.COM Github: https://github.com/halowe94

Portfolio: https://halowe94.github.io/hlowe-portofolio/

# Haley Lowe

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate full-stack web developer with a background in human services. Utilizing interpersonal experience to create web applications that meet client needs. Earned Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from UC Davis where over 200 classroom hours were devoted to programming skills in Javascript, CSS, Node, React, MySQL, and MongoDB. Adept at inquiry and learning quickly. Intent on making a positive impact through technology.

#### SKILLS

Languages: HTML/CSS, Javascript

Libraries/Tools: Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Git, Node.js, React

Other: Heroku, Mongo Atlas, Postman, Netlify, Babel, Shopify, Troubleshooting issues

with hardware and software, teaching and collaborating remotely

### **PROJECTS**

## Journey On | https://halowe94.github.io/JourneyOn/

This web application allows users to easily check the weather and forecast of their destination, find nearby restaurants, and translate English into their destination's language.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 to design UI, utilize APIs, and debug code
- Completed web application remotely utilizing Zoom, Slack and Github
- $\bullet$  Front End Developer employed Javascript to create ajax calls to multiple APIs, routing, and UX
- Navigated version control through VS Code, Git, and Github
- HTML/CSS, Javascript, APIs

## Table of Continents | <a href="https://stark-stream-40899.herokuapp.com/">https://stark-stream-40899.herokuapp.com/</a>

A full stack web application that utilizes express, sequelize, handlebars, and node to enable the user to toggle between web pages and learn few facts and popular dishes from each continent.

- Full Stack Developer Coded middleware to connect front end and back end, created file structure, added MySQL database
- Merged branches on github and facilitate meetings to ensure regular pulls/pushes
- Deployed application through Postman and Heroku
- Led team through troubleshooting and created solutions to unforeseen problems
- HTML/CSS, Javascript, APIs

#### Food Bank Finder | Deployment coming soon

This application allows the user to find the top three nearest Food Bank Locations and map to those locations.

- Applied Agile techniques to monitor completion of tasks within team
- Presented application to industry professionals to receive feedback for continued development
- Maximized use of newly learned library (React) by building components for index and about page
- Tested various map APIs and plugins for functionality within React components
- Formatted CSS for responsive web design
- HTML/CSS, Javascript, APIs

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Computing For All,

Web Development Teacher

Seattle, WA -

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

- Managed high school classroom and guided students in troubleshooting computer difficulties
- Taught students coding skills ranging from basic html to advanced javascript, implementing Node.js, Express, React, SQL, MongoDB, and Ajax
- Created lesson plans for both in-person and remote learning to ensure completion of learning outcomes

## Amazon Inc,

Sacramento, CA -

Warehouse Associate

JULY 2020 - JANUARY 2021

- Participated in multi-faceted process to fulfill customer orders, including cross-training in multiple department to increase company productivity.
- Engaged in diverse cross-departmental communication on a daily basis with coworkers to ensure proper procedures were followed.

#### Adventures in Missions,

18 countries -

Team Leader, Team Treasurer, Volunteer

JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2020

4 temporary assignments over the course of 5 years: Jan-Apr 2015, Aug-Dec 2016, Jun 2018-Jun 2019, Jan-Apr 2020

- Directed young adults in group feedback, provided mentorship, and mediated conflicts which created a collaborative environment
- Managed spending and recorded expenses for a budget of \$3k-\$7k for a team of 5-18 people for a combined time of 1 year, allowing for team to maximize impact within budget
- Adapted to cultural contexts in order to bolster strategic partnerships with local organizations

#### Boosterthon,

Sacramento, CA -

Program Specialist

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

• Facilitated engaging presentations and group discussions about character development to school administration and students (ages 4-13) to increase school-wide participation in the fundraising programs of 23 schools

#### Kids Overcoming Inc,

Citrus Heights, CA -

Registered Behavior Technician

JANUARY 2018 - JULY 2018

- Assisted in training new employees in utilizing proper ABA protocol in varying environments with multiple families and children (ages 3-13) to assure continued success of the client
- Maintained data collection, behavior management programs, and consistent communication with clinicians so that their was no accurate documentation for treatment plans

## **EDUCATION**

## The Seattle School of Theology and Psychology - SEATTLE, WA

M.A. in Counseling Psychology (concentration in trauma and abuse)

Expected Graduation: June 2024

## UC Davis Continuing and Professional Education - REMOTE

Full-stack Web Development Certificate

JUNE 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

A six month intensive program that focused on MERN stack + HTML, CSS, Javascript, APIs, MySQL, NoSQL, testing basics, and progressive web applications

#### Colorado Chrsitan University- LAKEWOOD, CO

B.A. in Intercultural Ministry & Leadership, B.A. in Social Science (emphasis in Psychology)

 Studies focused on working between cultures, leadership style and leading groups/organizations, theology, and numerous social sciences including macro-economics, family psychology, and cross-cultural communication

## **AWARDS**

Graduated Cum Laude Outstanding Senior in Social Science